《我们的生活》前情回顾
Previously on This Is Us...
妈最近出现了认知功能障碍
Mom is suffering from cognitive impairment.
是妈不让我告诉你们的
Mom asked me not to tell you guys.
她看你们压力大  不想你们为她担心
She didn't want to add any more stress to your plates.
这周末我来照顾杰克吧
Let me take care of Jack this weekend.
我需要和我的儿子待在一起
I need to spend time with my son.
喜欢吗
You like it?
凯特
Hey, Kate.
我是麦迪逊  我和凯文上床了
It's Madison. I slept with Kevin!
很久以来  我都很焦虑...
I've been anxious for so long.
贝丝觉得我应该去看看心理医生
Beth thinks I should see a therapist.
也许你应该去看看
Well, maybe you should.
抱歉我回来晚了
Sorry I'm late, guys.
我已经尽力
I got out of there
尽快赶过来了
just as soon as I could.
今天是成绩单日
Report Card Day.
-他们一直在等你  -成绩单日
- They've been waiting. - Report Card Day.
开始吧
Let's... do this, huh?
-这表情有点严肃  -是啊
- Oh, that is a serious face. - Oh, yeah.
小贝  可能是坏消息
Bec, this is bad news.
难道  他一直以来的
I think, maybe, could it be his...
连A常胜期结束了吗
straight-A streak is over?
几何学得了A-
Oh, an A-minus in geometry.
绝对要禁足你
Oh, you are so grounded.
我花太多时间在数学奥林匹克竞赛上
I'm putting too much time into Mathletes
结果真正的数学反而差了
and not enough time into actual math.
别这样  这成绩很好了
Oh, no, hey, come on, this is great, pal.
真的  别在意
Really. Forget it.
-宝贝  你还好吗  -等等...
- Bug, are you okay? - Wait, so...
也许她在虚张声势
she could be bluffing.
-是虚张声势吗  -是吗
- Is she bluffing? - Is she?
生物进步了
Improvements in biology...
-公民课也是  -凯特  这成绩多好啊
- and civics. - Yeah, Kate, this is great.
-怎么了  -斯图尔特跟我分手了
- What's wrong? - Stuart broke up with me.
-亲爱的...  -不
- Aw, hon... - No.
我要一个人待着  别跟来
I need to be alone. Don't follow me.
-凯特宝贝  -没事
- Katie girl... - No, no, I...
-我来处理  -好
- I will handle that. - Sure.
我们看完凯文的成绩  我就上楼去
Let's do Kevin quickly, and then I'll go upstairs.
你这表情非常骄傲啊  小兄弟
Oh, that's a very smug mug, sir.
难道是...
Can it be...?
两个 A
Two As, baby.
什么
What?
体育和艺术课而已
Yeah, in P.E. and art.
其他都是C  还有2个D
The rest are Cs and two Ds.
"扰乱课堂"  "迟到"
"Disruptive in class." "Arrives late."
"总想得到注意力"  凯文
"Needs to be center of attention"? Kevin.
两个A就是两个A
Two As are two As.
妈妈说过  我每得一个A就给我五块钱
Mom said I'd get five dollars for every "A."
我跟你赌五块钱  你不知道加起来等于多少
Bet you five bucks you don't know what that adds up to.
我要拿赚的钱
I'm gonna buy an entire box of
买一整盒棒球卡
baseball cards with my winnings.
我要对成绩提出异议
Yeah, well, I'm gonna contest my grade.
下周就改成A了
That'll be an "A" by next week.
兰德尔  其实这样也没关系
You know, Randall, it wouldn't hurt you to...
别对自己这么严格
to lighten up on yourself.
不行  我一定要解决
No way. I'm going to fix this.
记得给我十块钱  说话算话
Hey. Ten bucks. American.
只要我跟霍林斯老师聊过
The second I talk to Mrs. Hollins,
就会给我改成A了
it'll be up to an "A."
亲爱的
Hey, babe?
兰德尔情况更严重了
Randall is getting worse.
我们要不要找谁聊聊  比如辅导员之类的
Do we need to talk to someone, like a guidance counsellor
-或者...  -不用  他就是比较紧张
- or a...? - No, come on, he's just, he's wound up tight.
没事的  他就是需要释放一下
All right? He needs to blow off some steam.
释放一下
Blow off steam?
别担心  我来处理  你去吧
Don't worry about it. I got it. Go on.
好
Okay.
你还好吗
Everything okay?
挺好的  为什么这么问
Uh, yeah, why?
没什么  就是觉得你去过小屋之后
I don't know, just thought you'd be
应该会更放松一些
a little more refreshed after a weekend at the cabin.
妈今天下午就会收到
Ah. Um, Mom's getting the results
核磁共振报告的结果
for her MRI this afternoon,
我能感觉到她有点紧张
and I can tell she's a little nervous.
不能亲自陪着她我有点难受
Just really hate not being there in person.
不过你可以在心理咨询时聊聊这个呀
But, hey, that's something you could talk about in therapy,
-对不对  -是
- right? - Yeah.
我真为你骄傲
I'm so proud of you.
这是一大步
This is a big step.
没什么大不了的
It's not that big of a deal.
好
All right.
没什么大不了
No big deal.
对了  安妮的生日要到了
Uh, so, hey, listen, you know, Annie's birthday is coming up,
我在想...
and I was thinking...
你之前总说的有机蜂蜡唇膏
Have you still got that organic beeswax balm
-你还有吗  -喂  别乱翻我包
- you keep talking about? - Hey, out of my purse, man.
哇这么凶
What are you...? Aah! What?
-我在想...  -谢谢
- And I was thinking... - Thank you.
要不要给她买一部手机
that we could get her the iPhone.
我们说好的  初中才能买手机
We agreed no iPhones until junior high.
我知道  但是她求我的时候太可爱了
I know. But, you know, she's so cute when she begs.
她卖起萌来太有杀伤力了
You know, the Force is strong with that one.
但我们立场更坚定
But it is stronger in us.
至少现在很坚定
At least it is now.
我喜欢你涂润唇膏
I love your lip balm.
我爱你的美貌
I love your face.
早上好
Morning.
你起得好早
You're up early.
咖啡刚做好
Coffee's fresh.
我的天
My goodness.
妈妈昨晚从木屋回到家的时候
Someone was asleep when Mommy got home last night
有个宝宝睡着了
from the cabin.
我知道昨晚我们没来得及聊
Um, I know we didn't really get a chance to talk last night,
那我先开始
so I'll start.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我为所有的事道歉
For everything.
我出于害怕担心和疲惫
I said what I said out of...
才说了那些话
fear and-and worry and exhaustion,
如果我可以收回  我会收回
and if I could take it all back, I would.
但是
But...
原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
这个周末真是让我受益良多
This weekend was a real godsend.
翻译     青椒   春天里的小熊   InArance
废话少说
So without further ado,
你能跟我和杰克到车库去吗
would you please follow me and Jack to the garage?
翻译     学术男优   Lynn宁   Tracy-旋子
我们为你准备了一个惊喜
We have a surprise for you.
翻译     台风16   Funky   capitaljack
好了  你得发挥一下你的想象力
All right, you're gonna have to use your imagination here.
但我在想
But I was thinking...
校对     青椒  Funky   红枫
我们把车库
we turn the garage...
改成一个录音室  怎么样
into a music studio, huh?
时间轴     大葱  蒜头
现在  来  抱着他
Now-- here, take him--
这里还没
it's not all...
最后成型
up to scale...
后期     8T
但  这会是一个麦克风
But, uh, this would be... the microphone.
总监     红枫Gabriel
试音  一  二  三
Testing, one, two, three.
-跟上我  -托比
- So, stay with me. - Toby.
这是重头戏  准备好了吗
This is the pièce de résistance. Ready?
托比  拜托你停一停
Toby, please stop.
拜托了
Please.
我真的感激你做的这些事
I really appreciate what you're trying to do.
但是
But, you know,
一个周末之后
after one weekend...
我就是有点...
I'm just having tr...
这真的很好
This is very nice.
你做的这些很暖心
It's a very sweet gesture.
我  我就是需要一点时间
I-I just, I'm gonna need some time.
好吧
Okay.
怎么了
What?
没事吧  是你妈妈怎么了吗
Is everything okay? Is it your mom?
不是  是麦迪逊
No, it's Madison.
她跟凯文上床了
She slept with Kevin,
她想一起吃早午饭  跟我道个歉
so she wants to have brunch so she can apologize.
抱歉  我知道我们现在正在
I'm sorry, I know that we're kind of in the middle
处理问题  但你能允许我做个反应吗
of a thing right now, but permission to react?
可以
Yeah.
怎么回事
What?!
你跟你弟弟妹妹的
How was your trip
木屋之旅怎么样
with your brother and your sister?
非常好
Oh, the trip was great.
非常平和  很能增进感情
You know, very peaceful, lot of bonding.
-正是我需要的  非常好  -那就好
- Exactly what I needed. It was wonderful. - Yeah.
-很好  -你怎么样
- Nice. - How are you?
我很好
I'm good.
那就好  你看起来很好
Well, that's great. I mean, you look great.
-是吗  -是的
- I do? - Yes, you do.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
不是一般的好
Wonderful, actually.
他们跟你说了  是不是
They told you, didn't they?
什么  跟我说了什么  没有
What? Told me what? No.
凯文
Kevin.
兰德尔说漏嘴了
Randall let it slip.
宝贝  对不起
Sweetheart, I'm sorry.
-不用  -不  我想要亲自
- No. - No, I, I wanted to tell you
-告诉你的  -不不不  听我说
- in person myself. - No, no, no, no. Listen,
你不用担心我  懂吗
don't you worry about me, you understand?
我  我是来照顾你的
I'm... I'm here to take care of you.
好吗  你到底感觉怎么样
All right? How are you really feeling?
我知道你今天会知道核磁共振的结果  对吗
I know you have some MRI results coming back today, right?
-对  不过我很好  -好的
- Mm-hmm. I'm-I'm good, though. - Okay.
我很好  说实话我今天有点紧张
I'm good. I'm a little anxious about today, I'm not gonna lie,
但有趣的是  这些坏消息不知怎么地
but it's funny, somehow all of this bad news has sort of...
让我解脱了
freed me up.
让我想及时行乐
Carpe diem and all that.
你怎么样
Hey. How you doing?
很好
Ah. Good.
-很好  -是吗
- Good. -Yeah?
-综合考虑  挺好  -好吧
- All things considered, yeah. - Okay.
很好  天啊
Great. Well... Oh, man.
你们今天要做些什么
What-what-what are you guys doing today?
我们正计划着
Oh. We actually were planning on going to visit
去逛逛老式唱片店
some of those, um... old-fashioned record stores.
我们一直说想去来着
Something we say we always want to do,
但从来没去过  所以我们今天就去
and we never do it, so we're doing it.
有意思  我能去吗
Fun. Can I come?
你想去吗
You want to?
-当然  -我有个想法
- Yeah. - I got an idea.
要不你们去吧  好好享受一天
Why don't you two go off and make a day of it.
-就你们两个人  -你确定吗
- Just the two of you. - Are you sure?
当然  及时行乐的丽贝卡快把我累疯了
Yeah. Carpe Diem Rebecca is running me ragged.
只要确保在四点半看医生之前
You just make sure that you have her back in time
带她回来就好
for her doctor's appointment at 4:30.
-没问题  -好
- I can do that. - Okay.
来访请按铃  利医生
车上之家  2017最佳车型
-皮尔森先生  -是我  您好
- Mr. Pearson. - Yeah. Hello.
很高兴见到你  兰德尔
It's a pleasure to meet you, Randall.
请坐
Please sit.
你想喝点什么吗
Can I get you something to drink?
幸会
Likewise.
饮料不了  谢谢
And no, thank you.
这幅画是...
What's with the...?
我觉得它看着很舒服
I find it comforting.
如果我让你感觉无聊了的话
Well, at least you'll have something to look at
至少你还能看点别的
if I bore you.
所以  你今天为什么要来呢
So, what brings you here today?
说来话长
It's kind of a long story.
能耽误你一小时吗
You got an hour?
好的
Okay.
我们的生活 第四季第十五集
大家快点  你们上学要迟到了
Come on, guys. You're gonna be late for school.
小凯  请把棒球卡放回房间
Kev. Baseball cards back up in your room, please.
快点  凯文  我上课前要去找霍林斯老师
Hustle, Kevin. I'm meeting Mrs. Hollins before class
讨论改成绩的事
to talk about changing my grade.
你能放学后带我去棒球卡店吗
Can you take me to the baseball card store after school?
不行  抱歉  我没时间
Nope. I'm sorry, I don't have time.
我得去办事  要去杂货店  银行
I have errands to run: grocery store, bank,
图书馆  干洗店  抱歉
library, dry cleaning. Sorry.
那你能把两个A的钱给我吗
Then, can you give me the money for my two As?
我想一整天都感受它在我口袋中的热度
I want to feel it burning in my pocket all day.
凯文
Kevin!
小凯  快点  把棒球卡放楼上
Hey, Kev, come on, baseball cards upstairs.
兰德尔  你记得我会去学校接你吧
Randall, you remember I'm picking you up from school?
-东西收拾好了吗  -嗯
- You got your stuff? - Yeah.
好  很好  去车里等吧
Okay, good. Wait in the car.
凯特  快下来
Hey, Kate? Come on!
宝贝
Bug?
该出发了
It's time to go.
我走  还是留下
I go. I stay.
有什么关系呢
What does it matter?
我今天晚点要去趟市场
I'm gonna go to the market a little later today.
你晚餐有什么想吃的吗
Do you have any requests for dinner?
三芝士通心粉
Three-cheese macaroni?
没问题
You got it.
要不放学后
How about after school
我陪你去办事
I come with you on your errands,
然后我们顺路去趟卡片店可以吗
and then we can swing by the card store afterwards?
好吧
Fine.
好了  我们走
Okay, let's go.
我怀念音乐开始前
I miss that crackle
唱片发出的噼啪声
on the record before the music.
琼尼·米歇尔  《云》
琼尼...
Joni...
我能花几个小时盯着这张专辑封面
I would spend hours staring at this album artwork.
阅读所有内页说明
Reading all the sleeve notes.
好吧  真老套
Okay, boomer.
随你怎么笑话我
You can laugh at me all you want,
但我的唱片收藏...
but my record collection...
就是我的整个世界
was my whole world.
有点像你和你的棒球卡似的
Kind of like you and your baseball cards.
好吧
Oh, okay.
好吧  不  我的棒球卡是
All right, no, my-my baseball cards, that,
那是  那是正经八百的
that was, that was real,
那才叫收藏  好吗
that was a collection, okay?
既讲究策略  也得有商业头脑
There-there was strategy involved, there was commerce.
-相当复杂  -我可都记得
- I mean, the whole thing. - Oh, I remember.
对吧
Yeah.
我跟你说过我和你爸
Did I ever tell you the first time
第一次来洛杉矶时
your father and I came out to L.A.,
我们想找琼尼·米歇尔的故居
we tried to find Joni Mitchell's old house
好像是在月桂谷
in, um, Laurel Canyon?
我们好像已经开过奥林匹斯山了
I think we passed Mount Olympus.
你确定没把地图拿倒吗
You sure the map's not upside-down?
没有
No.
我们已经到附近了  甚至
We got close, we even
在琼尼住的街区转了几圈
wandered around Joni's neighborhood,
但却没有找到房子
but we never found the house,
于是...我们就放弃了
so... we gave up.
也许我们应该完成这个任务  对吗
Maybe we should finish the job, you know?
我们要找到琼尼·米歇尔的故居
We'll find Joni Mitchell's old house.
怎么找呢
How?
你好Siri
Hey, Siri?
琼尼·米歇尔的故居在哪
Where's Joni Mitchell's old house?
-你在做什么  -这是我搜索到的结果
- What are you doing? - Here's what I found on the Web.
是这个吗  她的故居
Is that it? That her house?
-天呐  是的  -是吗
- Oh, my goodness, yes! - Yeah?
对  就是这幢房子
Yes, that-that's the house.
但你觉得我们去看医生之前
Well, uh, do you think we have time, though,
还有时间吗
before your doctor's appointment?
就算没时间也要挤出时间
Well, if we don't have time, we're gonna make time.
-好啊  及时行乐的丽贝卡  -对的
- Okay, Carpe Diem Rebecca. - Yes.
我们出发吧
Here we go, all right.
好姐妹
Hey, girl.
快过来
Get over here.
很高兴见到你
It's nice to see you.
这地方是不是很赞
Isn't this place cute?
我超喜欢来这里吃早午餐
I love coming here for brunch.
这里很时髦但又不过火
It's hip but still normal...
好了  麦迪逊  我们直奔主题吧
Okay, Madison, let's just cut the preamble.
我们快点把事情解决
Okay, let's just get it over with.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
你对我来说太重要了
You are so important to me,
而闺蜜之间是不会互相伤害的
and friends don't do that to friends.
也不会和闺蜜兄弟上床
Or their brothers.
说实话  我都不知道自己当时在想什么
Honestly, I don't know what I was thinking.
我只知道  我从没见过这么性感
Other than I have never seen anyone so hot
又同时这么脆弱的人
and so vulnerable at the same time.
我脑袋就短路了
My brain just shorted.
我知道他是你哥哥  但是...
I mean, I know he's your brother, but...
我的天
my God.
我真的很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我很羞愧也很难为情
I am ashamed and embarrassed,
这事再也不会发生了
and it'll never happen again.
我真的不知道该怎么看待这件事
I really don't know what to think about all of this.
而且在这个节骨眼发生  真的太糟糕了
And it really couldn't have come at a more terrible time.
健身房那个贱人又惹事了吗
Is it that CrossFit bitch?
我要杀了她
I'll kill her.
是托比的问题
Is it Toby?
那我杀了他
I'll kill him.
你发句话
You just say the word,
我就把他们一一解决
I will Kill Bill all of them
然后亲自帮你把孩子养大
and help you raise that child myself.
跟我说说  凯特
Talk to me, Kate.
求求你了
Please?
所以我们该怎么做  医生
So, how we doing this, Doc--
像《心灵捕手》
is it Good Will Hunting
还是《黑道家族》那样
or The Sopranos?
别介意  我只是开玩笑  我...
No, I'm just playing. I, um...
我把自己的情绪表达出来之后会很舒服
I'm comfortable speaking about my emotions.
我是个感情丰富的人
I'm an emotional man.
不会因此不好意思
No shame.
在我们开始前  让我...
before we start, let me just...
把手机调成静音
...put this on silent.
我妈妈今天要见医生
My, uh, mom's got a doctor's appointment today,
但我没必要因此分心  对吧
but there's no need for any distractions, right?
好了
Okay.
剩下的交给你了
All yours.
她还好吗
Is she okay?
她还好
Ah, she's fine.
痴呆的早期症状
Um, early signs of dementia,
但在掌控之中
but we're on top of it.
今天只是后续的复诊
Today's just a follow-up appointment,
但我不是因为这个才来这里
but that's-that's not why I'm here.
那你为什来这里
So, why are you here?
我有焦虑症
I have anxiety.
患有  是这个叫法吗...
Suffer from, is that the...?
无所谓了
Doesn't matter.
大约每隔十年  事情会变得太...
Maybe once every decade things get too...
难以承受
overwhelming.
急性焦虑症就会发作
I'll have a panic attack.
我就要入院接受治疗
I'll be hospitalized.
这种情况发生过两次
That's happened twice.
最近我家遭遇了入室偷窃
My house was recently broken into.
我妻子担心我的焦虑症又会发作
My wife's worried about history repeating itself.
我的女儿  苔丝...
So, my-my daughter Tess...
我有三个女儿
uh... I have three daughters.
而且  苔丝在看心理医生
Anyway, Tess sees a therapist.
对她帮助挺大的
Um... it's really helped her.
所以  我想这就是我想要摆脱焦虑的
So, I think that's what I'm looking to get out of this is
应对机制
coping mechanisms.
好的  在我们聊这件事之前
Okay, well, before we get to that,
我想再了解一下你
I'd like to know a little more about you.
我是个很容易了解的人  你想从哪里开始
I'm an open book-- where do you want to start?
从出生开始吗
The beginning?
我其实是被领养的
So, I'm actually adopted.
我出生那天被遗弃在一个消防站
I was left at a fire station the day I was born,
然后一个消防员带我去了医院
and a fireman took me to the hospital,
他在医院遇到我父母...
where he met my parents...
不好意思
I'm so sorry.
为了防止话题跑得太远
Before we get too far into the weeds here,
在你和盘托出之前...  我知道你是谁
full disclosure-- I do know who you are.
我其实在你的一次演讲中听到过这个故事
I've actually heard that story in one of your speeches.
其实你很多演讲中都说过
In many of your speeches, actually.
原来你知道
Oh, you know...
我的演讲
...my speeches.
-妈  -怎么了  凯文
- Mom? - Yes, Kevin?
-棒球卡  -还不行
- Baseball cards. - Not yet.
太不公平了
So unfair.
生活就是不公平的
Well, so is life.
因为凯特被甩了  你就给她做
Look, you-you're making Kate's favorite dinner
她最爱的晚餐
because she got dumped.
因为兰德尔是个大呆子
And you're returning Randall's library books
你还帮他还从图书馆借的书
because he's a massive nerd.
你至少也得让我
The least you could do is give me
在棒球卡商店待五分钟吧
five minutes at the baseball card store.
我并不是单纯因为凯特逛杂货店的
Uh, I didn't go to the grocery store just for Kate.
我还买了菜  里面有两只鸡
I also bought groceries, including two chickens
要做给全家人吃呢
that I will cook for the whole family.
你要是能像索菲的妈妈那样多好啊
I wish you were more like Sophie's mom.
她就很有趣
She's fun.
我也很有趣啊
Uh... I'm fun.
我和索菲的妈妈一样有趣
I am as fun as Sophie's mom.
我是个有趣的妈妈
I am a fun mom.
等一下  你是认真的吗
Oh, wait, are you being serious?
好吧
Okay, fine.
好吧  我们去棒球卡商店
Fine. We will go to the baseball card store.
-太棒了  -因为我是个有趣的人
- Yes. - Because I'm fun.
-但只有五分钟  -好
- But five minutes only. - Okay.
五分钟  凯文  你听到了吗
Five minutes, Kevin, you hear me?
-明白  -我认真的  我们买了菜
- Got it. - Seriously. We have groceries,
还买了冷冻蔬菜
including frozen vegetables
-还有乳制品  -好  谢谢
- and dairy. - All right. Thank you.
我真不敢相信我来了这里
I cannot believe I'm here.
-是的  -凯文
- Yeah. - Kevin.
琼尼·米歇尔和格雷厄姆·纳什
You know, Joni Mitchell lived in this house
曾经住在这里
with Graham Nash.
等一下  你要干什么
Wait, what are you doing?
按门铃啊
I was gonna ring the bell.
你不想看看里面吗
Don't you want to see inside?
不请自来有点莽撞了吧
Isn't that rude to just show up unannounced?
说来不是很公平  但做名人的好处
It's not fair, but being a celebrity is like having
就是基本上你想做的任何事
a Fast Pass to pretty much everything
都有捷径
you want to do in life.
把屋里没人变成有人  还是做不到
Except of course making people magically home.
妈
Mom?
开着的
It's open.
门是开着的  来
It's open. Come on.
-妈  -来啊
- Mom. - Come on.
好吧  如果我因为和我妈
All right. If I end up on TMZ
闯入琼尼·米歇尔故居
for breaking into Joni Mitchell's old house
上了网络头条...
with my mom...
其实这主意不错啊
Actually, I mean, that could play.
爸  我体育课拿了A
Hey, Dad? I have an "A" In P.E.
我真的不需要这么做
I really don't need to be doing this.
这和成绩无关  兰德尔
It's not about grades, Randall.
锻炼是为了
Exercise is about
让你全身的血液流通起来
getting blood moving through your whole body.
好吗  现在  我要你一直跑
Okay? Now, I want you to run until that worried feeling
跑到你肚子里的担忧消失为止
in the pit of your stomach goes away.
我真的不喜欢跑步
I really don't like running.
是吗  那比赛怎么样
Yeah. How about racing?
怎么样  来吧
Huh? Come on.
你和我  绕跑道跑一圈
You and me, once around the track.
我甚至可以让你先跑
I'll even give you a head start.
好
Yeah.
能帮我个忙吗
Hey, just do me a favor?
尽量让比赛有趣点
Try and make it interesting.
好了  运动员
Okay, runners.
各就各位...
On your marks...
预备...
get set...
跑
Go!
我大概是想说
I guess what I'm saying is,
我很幸运我是被两位杰出的父亲
I'm fortunate to have been shaped
塑造出来的...
by two incredible fathers--
一位得而复失  一位失而复得
the one I lost and the one I gained.
我会在演讲里说这些是有道理的
It's in my speeches for a reason.
-当然  -是啊  当然
- Of course. - Yeah, of course.
我忍不住觉得
You know, I can't help but feel
我像是一直在自曝其短
like I'm throwing off my back foot here.
就像你已经谷歌了我  这不违反规定吗
It's like you googled me. Isn't that against the rules?
我觉得你这样等着我
I mean, I just find it weird
自己提起这些事是很诡异的
that you waited to bring that up.
你早就知道...
You knew...
不  抱歉
No, I'm sorry.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
想被以礼相待  先要以礼待人  对吧
I'm only gonna get out of it what I put in, right?
不是你的错
Not your fault.
我是个公众人物  我不应该因此大惊小怪的
I'm a public figure-- I shouldn't have been surprised.
我们说到哪里了
Where were we?
家庭
Family.
家庭  对
Family. Sure. Of course.
我告诉他  仅仅是想要
I just told him it-it wasn't enough
当一个好爸爸
for him to want to be
是不够的
a good father.
他必须成为一个好爸爸
Just needs to be one.
我现在都不知道他是真心的
And now I don't even know if he's being sincere
还是只是在说我想听的话
or if he's just telling me what I want to hear.
不能两者都是吗
Could it be both?
相信我  你现在无论是什么立场
I mean... trust me, I will take whatever position
我都支持你
you take right now.
但是他听进去了你说的话也是有可能的啊
But is it possible he just took what you said to heart?
我不知道
I don't know.
你想知道我为什么和凯文睡了吗
Do you want to know why I think I slept with Kevin?
-不想  -跟一个
- No. Mm-mm. - It was nice to be
能体谅我的人在一起感觉很好
with someone who actually knew something about me.
不像是线上约会  或被安排相亲
As opposed to... Tinder dates or being set up.
他在医院看过我素颜的样子
I mean, he has seen me at the hospital with no makeup.
他还见过我在你家卸下矫饰的样子
And at your house not trying to be perky or appealing.
你和托比所拥有的  我所梦寐以求的
What you and Toby have, what I dream of finding,
就是那份亲密
is that intimacy.
它让你不再害怕被人发现
It's letting people see the worst part of you without...
自己的致命弱点
being scared.
下面这句话我说完就跑
And I am just gonna say this and duck.
难道托比不该表达出他最深的恐惧
But shouldn't Toby be able to express his deepest fears
且不用受到惩罚吗
without punishment?
婚姻不就是如此吗
Isn't that what marriage is?
好吧
Okay.
你什么时候变成《单身汉天堂》
When did you become the counselor of relationships
里面的情感顾问了
with Bachelor in Paradise?
我听了许多情感类播客的节目
I listen to a lot of relationship podcasts.
一直希望自己有一天能用上
I keep hoping I'll need them someday.
所以  我们和好了吗
So, are we good?
和好了
Yes.
但你还处于考察期
But you're on probation.
你是爱我的
You love me.
大多数时候吧
Most of the time.
我能告诉你一件你哥对我干的事吗
Can I just tell you one thing your brother did to me?
-不能  -某个瞬间我整个人是倒过来的
- No. - I was literally upside-down at one point.
-麦迪逊  -发挥你的想象力
- Madison. - Just use your imagination.
91系列的卡还有剩的吗  卡尔
You got any '91s left, Carl?
不多了  你要什么  小凯
Not many. What are you looking for, Kev?
还缺一张约翰·坎德拉里亚才能集齐去年那套
I need a '91 John Candelaria to finish off last year's set.
我有10美元可以买卡
I got ten bucks to do it.
我只剩下16包了
Well, I've got only 16 packs left,
我觉得你能找到的几率很大
but I like your chances of finding it.
太好了  我都买了  谢谢你
Great, I'll take 'em. Thank you.
8美元40美分
Eight dollars and 40 cents.
好了
Right.
没有约翰·坎德拉里亚吗
No John Candlemalaria?
没有吗
No?
打起精神来  宝贝
Well, buck up, sweetheart.
你还剩下14包呢
You have, what, 14 packs left?
往这包上吹气  讨个好运
Here. Blow on this one... for good luck.
天啊  这个口香糖真不咋地
Oh, gosh, this gum is really not very good.
味道只持续一分钟
The flavor only lasts a minute.
每60秒都要换一片口香糖
You got to replace it, like, every 60 seconds.
-我觉得这包有希望  -真的吗
- I feel good about this one. - Yeah?
没错  快拆吧
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
好
Cool.
击球手准备  准备  准备  挥棒
Batter, batter, batter, swing!
快拆吧
Come on.
你知道格雷厄姆·纳什写的《我们的家》
Did you know that Graham Nash wrote the song "Our House"
就是以这里为原型吗
about this house?
-真的吗  -是的
- Oh, really? - Mm-hmm.
某天早上琼尼和格雷厄姆去了圣费尔南多山谷
One morning Joni and Graham went down to the Valley
来到一家熟食店吃早餐
to have breakfast at Art's Deli.
早餐后
And after breakfast
他们沿着万特乐大道散步
they were walking down Ventura Boulevard,
琼尼透过商店橱窗发现了她非常喜欢的花瓶
and Joni spotted this vase in a store window that she really liked.
所以他们就买下了它
So they bought it.
然后他们把它带回家  格雷厄姆生火的时候
And they brought it back home, and Graham suggested
提议琼尼为花瓶挑选一些花
that Joni pick some flowers for the vase while he built a fire.
*我会生起火*
*I'll light the fire*
*你把花朵*
*You place the flowers*
*插进你今天买的花瓶里*
*In the vase that you bought today*
*盯着火焰*
*Staring at the fire*
*久久不肯移走目光*
*For hours and hours...*
-一起唱  杰克  -不了
- Come on, Jack. - No, no, I...
*当我聆听你*
*While I listen to you*
*整晚为我*
*Play your love songs*
*演奏情歌*
*All night long for me*
*只为我一人*
*Only for me-ee-ee*
*现在到我身边来*
*Come to me now*
*安心倚靠五分钟*
*Rest your head for just five minutes*
*一切*
*Everything*
*都已尘埃落定*
*Is done.*
你还记得歌词
You still got it.
如果不是因为这首歌  我可能就忘记了
An otherwise simple morning might have been forgotten
那个简简单单的早晨
if it weren't for that song.
你害怕吗
Are you scared?
有点
A little.
但我现在一点也不会去想那些事
But I'm not even thinking about any of that right now
因为  你现在陪在我身边
'cause I am... I'm right here with you.
你总是拥有那种能力  凯文
You've always had that quality, Kevin.
你让一切都变得有趣起来
You make everything fun.
我知道  你或许有时觉得这是个缺点
Which I know you probably think is a bad thing sometimes,
或许人们因此不会把你当回事
and maybe people don't take you seriously.
你太心灰意冷了  让我试试  让我试试
You're ice cold. Let me try. Let me try.
准备好了吗
Ready?
加油  加油
Okay. Okay.
不是
Nope.
不是那张
It's not it.
怎么了
What?
有时你会让人们忘记自己的烦恼
Sometimes making people forget about their worries,
或者将来会发生什么
or what comes next--
这是你能给别人最重要的帮助
that's the most important thing you can do for someone.
我们刚才聊了你的焦虑发作情况
So, we've talked about your panic attacks
还有你和你两位父亲的关系
and your relationship with your two fathers.
那你和你母亲关系如何呢
How is your relationship with your mother?
挺好的
It's good.
我爱我母亲
I love my mother.
我们关系很好
We're very close.
你要是觉得我此刻状态有点紧绷
If you sense me tensing up right now,
那是因为我担心她的病情
it's because of her illness,
并不是因为我和她关系不好
not because of my relationship with her.
我肯定不是因为她才来咨询的  相信我
Trust me when I say I'm not here because of her.
我来这里是因为我有情绪控制问题
I'm here because I have control issues.
你这是自我诊断的吗
Is that your... self-diagnosis?
我觉得这问题挺明显的
I think it's kind of obvious.
就像你现在努力想控制话题
Like how you're trying to control the conversation away
不愿讨论你母亲的事吗
from talking about your mom?
好了  梅尔菲医生
Okay, Dr. Melfi.
我明白了
I get it.
我明白你的意图了
I get what you're doing here.
到底是坏了还是怎么回事  为什么...
I mean, is it broke or something? What's the...?
你愿意说说你为什么会被那声音干扰吗
Do you want to talk about why that's bothering you?
这样我就不得不承认它干扰到我了
But then I would have to admit that it's bothering me.
好了  可以了
Okay. All right.
所以这些都是诊疗的一部分  是吗
So... this is all part of it, right?
包括等候室  还有那幅画
The waiting room, the painting?
这就是你诊疗的方式吗
Is that how your operation works?
激怒病人  从而让他们陷入精神崩溃
Just agitate your patients into having a breakdown?
抱歉
Apologies.
我看下信息
I need to check this.
这下好了
Oh, good.
看来今天是我哥带我妈
Looks like my brother will be taking my mom
去医院复诊
to her follow-up appointment today.
这下又会出什么问题呢
What could go wrong?
*我只能说我的生活平淡无奇*
*All I can say is that my life is pretty plain*
*我喜欢看着*
*I like watchin'*
*雨水汇入水洼...*
*The puddles gather rain...*
儿子  你先把东西拿到楼上去  好吗
Hey, bud, take your stuff upstairs, okay?
谢谢
Thanks.
*若问我怎么想...*
*And speak my point of view...*
我知道你不想聊斯图尔特  我理解
Look, I-I know you don't want to talk about Stuart, all right?
-尤其是跟你老爸聊这个  -我的确不想
- Especially not with your dad. - I don't.
有时候周六我做华夫饼时  你们经常会看到
Hey, do you know how, some Saturdays,
我把第一块饼扔掉了  你知道为什么吗
when I make waffles, you guys see me toss the first one out?
是因为电饼铛温度太高
That's because the waffle iron is too hot,
或者温度不够
or maybe it's not hot enough, or,
也有可能我把面糊倒太多了
you know, I made the batter too thick.
初恋男友呢  就有点像这第一块华夫饼
First boyfriends are kind of like first waffles.
明白吗  你要...
Okay? You-you got to...
经历过几次才能找到最合适的那一个
get through a few before you get it right.
你的那个人会出现的  他只是...
Yours is out there. He's just...
还没出炉呢
He's still cooking.
人呢
Hello?
谢天谢地你终于回来了
Thank God you're finally home.
他大概一小时前睡着了
He conked out, like, an hour ago,
我都不敢动怕吵醒他...
and I've been too afraid to move..
-你和麦迪逊聊得怎么样  -居然还挺好的
- How'd it go with Madison? - Surprisingly well.
她不会变成我大嫂吧  会吗
She's not gonna be my sister-in-law, is she?
不会  一切正常
No. It's all good.
小托
Tobe?
什么
Yeah.
我不想因为
I don't want to resent you
你坦诚说出你的感受而怨恨你
for being honest about your feelings.
我也不希望你
And I don't want you to resent me
因为我怨恨你而怨恨我
for resenting you about your feelings.
我爱你
I love you.
我受够了我们相互对立的状态
And I'm tired of the me versus you.
我们最好的状态是合起来一致对外
I mean, we're our best when it's me and you versus everyone.
-你知道吗  -知道
- You know? - Yeah.
我可以再去看看录音室吗
Now can I see the studio?
我知道我刚才打断了你  不过...
I know I cut it short before, but...
我觉得这是我认识你以来
I think it's one of your all-time...
收到过最甜蜜又浪漫的礼物之一了
sweetest, most romantic gestures.
说真的  它可以排第一
Actually, it's number one.
你刚才还没看完整间屋子呢
You just haven't seen the rest of it.
你能带我看看吗
Can you show me?
我好饿
Oh, I'm starving.
我们去吃点东西吧
Let's go get something to eat.
就去那家你喜欢的高档寿司餐厅怎么样
What about, um, that-that fancy sushi restaurant that you love?
可以  妈  不过我觉得时间可能会来不及
Uh... okay. I don't know if we have the time, though, Ma.
你看  我们要去接米格尔
I mean, uh, we got to get Miguel,
-然后我还要送你去看医生  -没事
- I got to get you to your doctor's appointment. - No.
没关系  那个可以改时间
No, we can reschedule that.
我可以试一下你常说的
Ooh, maybe I can try that dangerous food
那个危险食物  叫什么来着
you're always talking about. What's it called?
-河豚  -河豚啊
- The, the blowfish. - Blowfish.
-对  -没错
- Yeah. - Yes.
可是我...  我不想
Uh, yeah, I just... I don't want
让大家再次验证
to reinforce this family's narrative
凯文做事果然不靠谱
that I'm not dependable.
凯文  就拿个核磁共振报告而已
Kevin, they're only MRI results.
明天再去也行
They can wait until tomorrow.
妈...
Mom...
我不想...我不想去
I don't... I don't want to go.
因为我不想让今天结束
'Cause I don't want today to end.
今天无论如何都会结束的
Today's gonna end no matter what.
但我们还有明天
But there's tomorrow.
等到明天  我还会陪着你
There's tomorrow, and I will be here,
我们再去做些别的事
and we will do something else.
我保证
I promise.
控制一切不是出于我的需要
It's not that I need to be in control.
是我妈妈很依赖我
My mother depends on me.
只有我有能力照顾她
I'm the only one who can take care of her.
很久以来一直如此
It's been that way a long time.
没错
And, yes,
不用你搬出弗洛伊德那一套  我都知道
before you drop Freud on me, I get it.
我和我妈妈的关系非常复杂
I have a very complicated relationship with my mother.
可如果我不照顾她  谁照顾呢
But if I'm not the one who's taking care of her, who will?
她丈夫吗  他人是不错
Her husband? He's a nice guy,
但他几个月来都没察觉异样
but he's been missing this thing for months.
我哥吗
My brother?
你瞧好了  这个咨询结束之前
Just you wait. By the end of this session,
我就会收到消息  说我哥完全忘了时间
I'll get a text saying that he completely lost track of time
把医生预约的事忘了  还...
and forgot about the appointment, all the...
她确诊的时候
She made me promise
让我保证不告诉别人
not to tell anyone when she got diagnosed.
为什么
Why?
因为我哥还在戒酒瘾
Because my brother is a recovering addict.
我姐的小孩有特殊需要
My sister has a kid with special needs.
他们的日子够折腾了
They have enough on their plate.
好像我不折腾似的
As if I don't.
如果你觉得我才意识到这点
And if you think this is new information to me,
如果你觉得
if you think I'm having
我现在才豁然开朗  那可不是
some kind of revelation right now, I'm not.
所以来做咨询就是浪费时间
Which is why this is a waste of time.
我知道我的问题
I know my faults.
我知道我的情绪点在哪里
I know what triggers me.
但我认为我的问题是好问题
But I think my faults are good faults,
比起没有它们  我宁愿有
and I would rather have them than to not have them.
我知道你觉得我在说罗圈话
And I know you think I'm spiraling right now.
我在电视里看过  我知道怎么回事
I've seen the shows. I know the drill.
可是  如果没有我
But, hey, if it wasn't for me,
这整个家都会分崩离析
this whole family would have fallen apart.
会吗
Would they?
你...
You...
"会吗"
"Would they?"
你不会懂的
You don't get it,
我也没时间跟你解释
and I don't have time to explain it.
恕我直言
And, uh, due respect,
我怎么能向一个连2017年杂志都留着
how am I supposed to take mental health advice
饮水机旁的杯子用完了也不补充的人
from someone who doesn't throw out magazines from 2017?
听取心理健康建议呢
From someone who doesn't refill cups at the water cooler?
而且还挂了一幅...
From someone who put...
真没那么难  医生
It's not that hard, Doc.
爱你哦  爸爸  亲亲  苔丝
水烧开了就关掉
Just turn it off when you're done.
-你回来啦  -回来了
- Hey there. - Hey.
抱歉没回来吃晚餐
Sorry I missed dinner.
女儿们在哪呢
Where, uh, where are the girls?
黛佳在楼上跟马利克打视频
Uh, Deja's upstairs, FaceTiming with Malik.
苔丝和安妮在做作业
Tess and Annie are doing their homework.
好极了
Right on.
我尽力了  亲爱的
I tried, babe.
我只是觉得咨询不适合我
I just don't think it's for me.
我...
I...
至少...
Well, not...
至少现在不适合
At least not right now.
我没打算直接否决这个方式
I'm not closing the door on it.
好
Okay.
你还好吗
You good?
我就知道你会挑毛病
I knew you'd find something wrong with it.
我没有挑毛病
There's nothing wrong with it.
只是...
It's just, um...
我觉得你应该尽力试一试
I think you should try to give it a chance.
也许你应该再去几次
Maybe you should just go a couple more times,
-如果到时候还觉得...  -谢谢  贝丝
- and-and then if you still think that... - Thank you, Beth,
我没事
but I'm okay.
好吗  我知道你觉得我需要去
All right? And I know you think I need this,
-但...  -亲爱的
- but... - Babe?
是我需要你去
I need this.
你说什么
Sorry?
你想知道我今早为什么
You want to know why I didn't let you
不让你翻我的包吗
go through my purse this morning?
为什么
Why?
你给安妮买手机了
You bought Annie the iPhone.
这是一瓶防狼喷雾
It's a bottle of pepper spray
因为我有时得在晚上独自给工作室上锁
'cause sometimes I have to lock up the studio alone at night.
以前我没觉得有什么
And that didn't used to bother me,
但现在我会在意
but now it does.
这是处方药
This is doctor-prescribed.
我最近睡得不太好
You know, I haven't been sleeping very well.
医生开了三片药帮我应对失眠
She gave me three pills just to get me over the hump.
没错
And yeah.
这是给安妮准备的手机
This is a phone for Annie,
但并不是因为她想要手机
but it's not because she wants it.
而是因为我希望她能有部手机
It's because I want her to have it
因为曾有一个陌生人闯进我们家
because there was a strange man in our house,
所以我需要随时知道我的宝贝在哪里
and I need to know where my baby is at all times.
抱歉  贝丝  我不知道
I'm sorry, Beth, I didn't know.
你当然不知道
Of course you didn't.
因为我没有告诉你
'Cause I didn't tell you.
因为我很担心
Because I was worried
如果我再在你身上加根稻草
that if I lay anything else on you,
你就会被压倒
you were gonna crack.
但我想要告诉你
But I want to tell you.
我需要告诉你
I need to.
你是我男人
You're my person.
可除非你得到了你需要的帮助...
Unless you're gonna get the help you need...
不然我开不了口
...I can't.
蒙特利尔认知评估已经排除了
The MoCA test ruled out impairment
中风或肿瘤对认知的影响
due to stroke or tumor.
大脑的核磁共振显示
The brain MRI revealed
海马体出现了萎缩  这说明
hippocampal atrophy, which means
大脑中负责记忆的核心区域出现退化
shrinkage in the memory centers of the brain.
我们不能仅凭核磁共振的结果就确诊
We're not making a diagnosis based solely on the MRI,
不过海马体的萎缩可以证实
but hippocampal atrophy would support a diagnosis
之前诊断出的轻度认知障碍
of mild cognitive impairment,
可能是由阿尔茨海默症引起的
likely due to Alzheimer's,
这也给了我们清晰的诊疗思路
suggesting a clear course of action for us.
所以其实
So, the truth is,
我打扫车库并不只是为了你
I didn't clean out the garage just for you.
也是为了杰克
I cleaned it out for Jack, too.
因为这个录音室...
See, the music studio is for...
是给你们两个准备的
the both of you.
看
Ta-da.
什么
What?
当然  我们得随着他长大不断升级装备
Obviously, we will have to upgrade it as he grows,
舞动杰克·达蒙  宝贝
但如果有哪个孩子需要一间
but if any kid deserves a playroom
可以感受到所有声音的游戏室
with every sound known to man,
那一定就是舞动杰克·达蒙了
it is Jumpin' Jack Damon.
托比  我太喜欢了
Toby, I love it.
而且你说得没错
And you're right.
这份礼物绝对能排第一
This is the number one gesture.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-我早说了  -是啊
- Told you. - I know.
我去泡点茶
I'm gonna make some tea,
去拿点软糖准备享受电影之夜
gather up the Swedish Fish for movie night.
我想看《波拉特》
I'm thinking Borat.
太棒了
Perfect.
-亲爱的  -怎么了
- Sweetheart? - Yeah.
我想让你帮个忙  这个忙很重要
I have a favor to ask of you, and it's important.
好啊  什么都行
Yeah, anything.
不要特殊照顾我  好吗
Please don't start treating me any differently, okay?
我需要乐趣
I need the fun.
我需要大笑
I need the laughs.
我是说真的  凯文
I'm serious, Kevin.
我需要欢乐的你
I need that part of you.
好的
Okay.
而且我还很想去
I also really want to go
你在纽约的电影首映
to your movie premiere in New York.
我看到马特·达蒙带他妈妈去了
I see Matt Damon bringing his mom.
那不一样
That's different.
他们订婚了
They're engaged.
*如此舒适温暖的房间*
*Such a cozy room*
*窗户都被夜晚*
*The windows are illuminated*
*赐予光亮*
*By the evening*
*阳光照射窗户*
*Sunshine through them*
*仿若珠宝*
*Fiery gems*
*为了你*
*For you*
*只为了你*
*Only for you, ooh, ooh*
来啊  一起唱
Come on. Sing it.
*我们的家*
*Our house*
*是一栋非常非常好的房子*
*Is a very, very, very fine house*
-*非常好的房子*  -很好
- *Very fine house* - Nice.
*两只猫在院子里*
*Two cats in the yard*
-*在院子里*  -*生活曾如此艰难*
- *In the yard*- *Life used to be so hard*
*但现在一切都很轻松*
*Now everything is easy*
-*都是因为你*  -*因为你*
- *'Cause of you*- *'Cause of you.*
舞动杰克·达蒙  宝贝
那天实在不好意思
Sorry about the other day.
我还不太习惯咨询
This is new for me.
不用在意
Don't mention it.
喝咖啡吗
Coffee?
不用了
I'm good.
-你介意我...  -随意
- You mind if I, uh...? - Sure.
多伦多蓝鸟队  约翰·坎德拉里亚
-多少钱  -两美元
- How much? - Two dollars.
太好了
Yes!
-抽到了  -总算抽到了
- Did it! - Finally.